Finding Aid for the Herschel Gower Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Herschel Gower Papers
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0176
7.51 linear_feet
Biographical Note
Herschel Gower, a native of Nashville, was born in 1919. He received his B.A. from Cumberland University in Lebanon, Tennessee and his master and doctorate degrees from Vanderbilt University. He spent 1954 - 1956 at the University of Edinburgh on a Fulbright Scholarship and has maintained a lifelong interest in Scottish culture and history.
He began his teaching career at Vanderbilt in 1956 in the English department and was awarded the title Professor Emeritus before his retirement from Vanderbilt in 1985. He taught courses in the ballad, the lyric, and American literature.
During his academic career he was a lecturer in the Vanderbilt in France study abroad program and at the University of Leeds for the Vanderbilt in England program.
Professor Gower is the author and editor of a number of books including:
Pen and Sword: The Life and Journals of Randal W. McGavock (1959)
The Sense of Fiction (1966)
The Hawk’s Done Gone and Other Stories by Mildred Haun (ed. 1968)
Beersheba Springs: A History and a Celebration (1983)
Faces in a Nashville Arcade (1983)
Jeannie Robertson: Emergent Singer, Transformative Voice (1995)
Charles Dahlgren of Natchez: The Civil War and Dynastic Decline (2002)
He has contributed articles and poems to scholarly publications, magazines, and newspapers, many with a focus on Tennessee history.
At present he is a free-lance writer and lectures at the Athena Foundation, a non-profit organization, started by his wife Dona. They live in Dallas, Texas and have a home in Beersheba Springs, Tennessee.
Scope and Content Note
This collection is primarily comprised of 6.05 linear feet of manuscript materials, which include drafts of an unpublished novel with its title and text changes in various versions. The papers also include manuscripts of his novel Faces in a Nashville Arcade and of his biography of Charles Dahlgren, Charles Dahlgren of Natchez: The Civil War and Dynastic Decline.
Professor Gower was a friend of writer Mildred Haun and her literary executor. His work as an editor of her stories is represented in these papers.
In addition there are articles and research notes and materials concerning Randal McGavock and his descendants, the Howell family and their descendants, and articles and books he wrote on the historic community of Beersheba Springs, Tennessee. There are subject files for his research on folklore, the D. Shelby Williams Trial which was used as background for his unpublished novel, and materials relating to poet John Crowe Ransom and author Peter Taylor.
A collection of correspondence and newspaper articles on the Yeatman and Polk families and their family ties with Gustave Eiffel, builder of the Eiffel Tower are included with these papers. There are fourteen reel to reel and cassette tape recordings, many of them songs recorded by the Scottish singer Jeannie Robertson.
- Correspondence
  - Cheney, Brainard and Frances Neel (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Davidson, Donald and Theresa (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lytle, Andrew (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ransom, John Crowe (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Wilson, Angus (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Beatty, Richmond C.; Cornell, Katharine F.; Ford, Jesse Hill; Moore, Mrs. Merrill; Ransom, Ellene; Rice, Cole Young; Taylor, Peter (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Writings by Gower
  - The Confessions of a Goo Goo Eater: An Odyssey of Nashville - a novel - typescript (early version of Faces in a Nashville Arcade)
  - Title page - page 48 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pages 49 - 102 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Pages 103 - 161 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Pages 162 - 177 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Pages178 - 209 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pages 210 - 227 and postscript (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Faces in a Nashville Arcade - novel - typescript with corrections
  - Introduction and Chapter I (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Title page - page 48 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Pages 49 - 102 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Pages 103 - 161 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Pages 162 - 177 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pages 178 - 209 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Pages 210 - 227 and postscript (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Faces in a Nashville Arcade - novel - typescript
  - Title page, introduction, and pages 1 - 48 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Pages 49 - 102 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Pages 103 - 161 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Pages 162 - 177 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Pages 178 - 209 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Pages 210 - 227 and postscript (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Faces in a Nashville Arcade - a novel published in 1983; letter from Joe S. Ellis for book cover photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Escape from Belle Meade - early drafts of a novel with corrections - holograph pages
  - Pages 1 - 37 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chapter III, pages 1 - 25 ( 2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chapter V (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chapter VII, pages 1 - 11 (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chapter IX (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chapter XI (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chapter XV - photocopies (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chapter XXIII - original and photocopies (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - XXV (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - XXVII (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - XXIX (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Photocopies of letters to Sarah Estin Treadwell (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Escape from Belle Meade - early drafts of a novel with corrections - typescript
  - Chapter II, pages 4 - 10, 20 - 21 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Chapter IV, pages 51 - 77, IB - 27B (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Chapter VI, pages 78 - 93, 1-B - 16 - B; Chapter VIII, pages 94 - 134, A-1 - A41 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Chapter X, pages 135 - 142 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Chapter XXX, pages 245 - 279 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Pages 280 - 297, C3a - C20 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pages 340 - 396 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Pages 456 - 467 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Pages 468 - 488, D13 - D32 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Pages 489 - 494 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Pages 505 - 508 (holograph copies) (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Writings
  - Escape from Belle Meade - typescript of a novel - masters with some corrections
    - Chapter I (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Chapter II (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Chapter III (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Chapter IV (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Chapter V (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Chapter VI (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Chapter VII (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Chapter VIII (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Chapter IX (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Chapters X and XI, XII, XIII (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Chapters XIV, XV (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Chapters XVI (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Chapter XVII (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - XVIII (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - XIX (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Writings
  - Escape from Belle Meade - typescript of a novel - old version
    - Part I: Escape from Belle Meade, pages 3 - 41 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Personae - The Treadwell Women, Chapters I - III, pages 1 - 73 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Chapter IV - pages 74 - 99 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Chapters V, VI, VII, pages 100 - 138 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Chapters VIII, IX, pages 139 - 176 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Chapters X - XIII, pages 177 - 212 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Chapters XIV - XVII, pages 213 - 259 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Chapters XVIII, XIX, pages 260 - 302 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Chapter XX, pages 303 - 322 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Chapter XXI, pages 1 - 22; Chapter XXIII, pages 1 - 25 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Writings
  - Lament for Eden - completed manuscript of a novel - version #5
    - Chapters 1 - III, pages 1 -72 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Chapter IV, pages 73 - 98 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Chapters V, VI, VII, pages 99 - 136 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Chapters VIII, IX, pages 137 - 173 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Chapters X, XI, XII, XIII, pages 174 - 207 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Chapters XIV, XV,XVI, XVII, pages 208 - 253 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Chapters XVIII, XIX, pages 254 - 296 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Chapters XX - XXI, pages 297 - 338 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Chapters XXII - XXV, pages 339 - 393 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Chapter XXVI - XXVIII, pages 394 - 433 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Writings
  - Lament for Eden - completed manuscript of a novel - version #5
    - Chapters XXIX, XXX, pages 434 - 465 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Chapter XXXI, pages 466 - 510 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Chapter XXXII - XXXVI, pages 511 - 554 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bloodlines - manuscript of a novel - version #6
    - Chapters I - III, pages 1 - 72 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Chapter IV, pages 73 - 94 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Chapters V, VI, VII, pages 95 - 129 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Chapters VIII, IX, pages 130 - 165 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Chapters X, XI, XII, XIII, pages 166 - 198 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Chapters XIV, XVII, pages 199 - 243 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Chapters XVIII, XIX, pages 244 - 296 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Chapters XX - XXI, pages 297 - 324 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Chapters XXII - XXV, pages 325 - 393 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Chapters XXVI - XXVIII, pages 394 - 433 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Chapters XXIX - XXX, pages 434 - 451 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Other manuscript chapters of the novel
    - Chapters II, XXII, XXIV (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Chapters XXV, XXVI (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Chapter XXVIII (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Maps (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Telling Blood - manuscript of a novel
    - Bound manuscript - final version (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Writings
  - The Vagaries of Valor: The Dahlgren Family in America (1996) - Original draft complete
    - Foreword, Prologue, Acknowledgements, Genealogical Charts, List of Illustrations, Chapter 1, pp. 1 - 15. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Chapters II, III, IV, pages 16 - 87 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Chapter V, pages 88 - 130 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Chapters VI, VII, pages 131 - 182 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Chapters VIII, IX, pages 183 - 239 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Chapters X, XI, pages 240 - 291 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Chapters XII, XIII, pages 292 - 330 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Chapters XIV, XV, pages 331 - 371 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Chapter XVI, Epilogue, pages 372 - 399 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Endnotes, Index, pages 400 - 428 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Charles Dahlgren of Natchez - manuscript published by Brassey’s
    - Chapter VI (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Chapter VII (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Articles by Gower
    - “A Brief History of Central Hall” (Vanderbilt University) with research notes, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - “Beersheba Springs and L. Virginia French: The Novelist as Historian” in Tennessee Historical Quarterly, Vol. XLII, no. 2, Summer 1983 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - “The Beersheba Diary of L. Virginia French, Part 1, Summer and Fall, 1863 (edited by H.G.) in East Tennessee Historical Society’s Publications, Nos. 52 and 53 ( 1981 and 1982). (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - “Getting It Straight From the Archives” paper presented to Friends of the Library, January 25, 2004 in Special Collections at Vanderbilt University (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Poems by Gower
    - “Mountain Storm” and others (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Writings by others, edited by Gower
  - Another Harvest of Scottish Ballads, 1951 - 1956 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Mildred Eunice Haun
  - The Hawk’s Done Gone and Other Stories - manuscript
    - Introduction, Prologue, the Pit of Death, pp. 1 - 53 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 3 - 4, pp. 54 - 100 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Chapters 5 - 6, pp. 101 - 134 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Chapters 7 - 8, pp. 135 - 180 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Chapters 9 - 10, pp. 181 - 228 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Chapters 11, pp. 229 - 254 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 12, pp. 255 - 281 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 13, pp. 282 - 304 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Other Stories - “Shin-Bone Rocks”; “The Piece of Silver”, pp. 305 - 354 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Other Stories - “A Feeling of Pity”; “For the Love of God and Sam Scott”, pp. 355 - 397 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Other Stories - “The Picture Frame”; “The Turkey’s Feather”, pp. 398 - 426 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Other Stories - “For Lead”, pp. 427 - 442 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Other Stories - “The Look”, pp. 443 - 490 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Other Stories - “ Dave Cocke’s Motion”, pp. 491 - 507 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Writings by Others, edited and re-written by Herschel Gower, 1968
- Mildred Eunice Haun
- Short Stories - manuscripts
  - “Runner Girl” - unpublished (192 pages)
    - manuscript, pages 1 - 45 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - manuscript, pages 46 - 90 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - manuscript, pages 91 - 130 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - manuscript, pages 131 - 160 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - manuscript, pages 161 - 192 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Short Stories - published and unpublished
    - “Dave Cocke’s Motion” - published (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - “A Feeling of Pity”; “For Lead” - published (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - “The Picture Frame” - published (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - “The Piece of Silver” - published (5 copies) (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - “Joe” - unpublished (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - “The Red Flower Pot” - unpublished (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - “The Root” (3 copies) - unpublished (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - “Then the Fire Went Out” - unpublished (3 copies) (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - “The Warping Bars” - unpublished (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - “When the Wind Blows” - unpublished (multiple copies) (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - “Yours Sincerely” - unpublished (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - untitled fragment (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - untitled fragment (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Other writings by Mildred Haun
    - “Barshia’s Horse He Made, It Flew” in American Prefaces, Vol. 5, no. 6, March 90; “The Turkey’s Feather” reprinted from the Georgia Review, Vol. VI, no. 4, Winter 1952 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Songs collected by Haun for Vanderbilt University thesis Cocke County Ballads and Songs under the direction of Professor Donald Davidson (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Photograph, newspaper articles and other papers relating to Haun’s life and work. (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Writings by others
    - Bradford, M.E. “Miss Eudora’s Picture Book” in The Mississippi Quarterly, Vol. XXVI, no. 4, Fall 1973. (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Subject and Research Files
  - Folklore
    - From Bishop Percy (1765) to John Jacob Niles (1974) 340 Books and Songs in the Berea College Collection, revised February 1974; Folklore and Oral History Catalogue from the University of Vermont Bailey/Howe Library, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Sadie Warner Frazer
    - Miscellaneous correspondence - includes plans for publication of her memoirs (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - “Reminiscences” (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Memoirs (1) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Memoirs (2) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Ed Harris
    - Parodies of famous poems presented at a party with correspondence and photograph (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Howell Family Genealogy with Texas connections
    - Genealogy charts and letters from Harriet Owsley, January 1986 and Dabney Hart, June 1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Isabel Elliott Howell
    - Humorous comments; “Reflections of Miss Rebecca McLemore” (Isabel Howell); “Only Slightly Acid: Observations About Her Life and Times”; newspaper articles (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Memorial tribute by Morton B. Howell; order of service, Downtown Presbyterian Church, Nashville; newspaper obituaries (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Randal McGavock and descendants (including Margaret Lindsley Warden)
    - Correspondence and articles (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Ed Gleeson concerning re-publication of Pen and Sword (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Pen and Sword reprint - correspondence and press releases with Richland Press (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, articles, and photograph ( 1851) (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Materials relating to the placing of a military marker on his grave at Mt. Olivet Cemetery in Nashville, TN, July 8, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Dixie Liberator and correspondence (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence and research papers (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Genealogy and Illinois McGavocks - correspondence and other papers (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Genealogy research and correspondence with Elizabeth Larkin (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Margaret Lindsley Warden, great niece of Randal McGavock and owner of his journals -newspaper articles and correspondence (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Subject and Research Files
  - John Crowe Ransom
    - “All Verse is Not Poetry” in Hika Magazine, December 1941 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - “A Tribute to John Crowe Ransom on His Seventy-fifth Birthday” in Shenandoah, Vol. XIV, No. 3, Spring, 1963; “John Crowe Ransom: Gentleman, Teacher, Poet, Editor, Founder of The Kenyon Review: A Tribute from the Community of Letters” in The Kenyon Collegian, supplement to Vol. LXXXX, no. 7, 1964. Gambier, Ohio (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Dedication of Ransom Hall, Symposium Held at Kenyon College, April 18, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Publications of Kenyon College (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Magazine and newspaper articles (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Memorial service, November 1, 1974; notes for the Vanderbilt Alumnus Magazine with correspondence (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Peter Taylor
    - Bibliography - note cards prepared by Herschel Gower (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Bibliography - note cards prepared by Herschel Gower (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Subject and Research Files
  - D. Shelby Williams Trial/Mary Washington Frazer Williams
    - Parts I and II (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Parts III (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Part IV (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Yeatman Family
    - Yeatmans - descendants of Gustave Eiffel and Thomas Yeatman, II - correspondence and articles (photocopies) (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Yeatman - Polk and Eiffel families - newspaper articles (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Savin Yeatman ( great great grandson of Thomas Yeatman, II and Gustave Eiffel) newspaper articles and correspondence on his visit to the U.S. in 1982 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - (Thomas Yeatman, II )“Peace and the Presidential Election of 1864” by Harriet Chappell Owsley reprinted from Tennessee Historical Quarterly, Vol. XVIII, Number 1, March 1959 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Ted P.Yeatman “Jesse James and Bill Ryan at Nashville” with newspaper article (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Letters - Yeatman - Polk Collection (Tennessee State Library and Archives) (1) photocopies (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Letters - Yeatman - Polk Collection (Tennessee State Library and Archives) (2) photocopies (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Letters - Yeatman - Polk Collection (Tennessee State Library and Archives) (3) photocopies (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Yeatman family - Book - Eiffel par Jean Prevost - Paris, M.CM. XXIX (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Yeatman and descendants - correspondence, newspaper articles, and photographs (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Yeatman family - correspondence, world’s fair at Knoxville, TN 1982, photograph of Savin Yeatman, Alison Gower, M. Alain de Bel at Knoxville World’s Fair (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Reel to reel tape recordings
  - Gaelic Folk Songs – Scotland #1 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Folk Songs and Music of Scotland #1 (Box 12)
  - Folk songs of Scotland Reel #2 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Folk Songs of Scotland Reel #3 (Box 12)
  - Folk Songs of Scotland Reel #4 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Folk Songs of Scotland Reel #5 (Box 12)
  - Note Cards With Contents of Recordings (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Reel to reel tape recordings
  - Cherry Tree Carol: Larry Austin, John Butcher, Judy Coffman, Betty McDavid, Corky McKee Med. Lyrics (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - a. Child Ballads from Several Scottish Singers. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Side 1:
    Margaret Stewart The Knight and the Shepherd’s Daughter
    Dowie Denso Yarrow
    Sir Hugh, or the Jew’s Daughter
    Baron o’ Braikley
    Sheila Stewart The Two Brothers
    Bella Stewart Higgins The Fause Knight Upon the Road
    Duncan McPhee The Fause Knight Upon the Road
    Nellie McGregor Higgins The Fause Knight Upon the Road
    Geordie Robertson The Bold Pedlar and Robin Hood
    John (Jack) Whyte The Two Sisters
    Margaret Stewart The Trooper and the Mind
    Jimmy Stewart Lord Randal
    Side 2:
    John Strachan Lang Johnny Mhor (exerpts)
    Jeannie Robertson Andrew Lammie
    Mrs. Elsie Morrison The Gardner
    Mrs. Jessie Murray Lord Thomas and Fair Ellender
    Jeannie Robertson Famous Flower of Serving Men
    John Strachan Robin Hood and Little John
    Willie McPhee The Farmer’s Curst Wife
    Willie Mathieson Capt. Wedderburn’s Courtship
    Mrs. Elsie Morrison The Laird o’ Drum
    John Strachan The Laird o’ Drum
    Keech in the Creel
    The Knight and the Shepherd’s Daughter
  - b. Ballad Tape for Herschel, with all the best from the School of Scottish Studies, Fair fa’ ye man! (Box 13)
  - a. Graduate English Club Lecture November, 17, 1961 in Old Central (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Introduction: Tom Inge (Box 13)
    - First Speaker: Mr. John Crowe Ransom [73] (Box 13)
    - Second Speaker: Dr. Donald Davidson [68] (Box 13)
    - b. Bettie McDavid, English 282, January 1966, “The Three Ravens” - versions from Bertrand Bronson, The Traditional Tunes of the Child Ballads (Box 13)
  - a. Jeannie Robertson Copied by Jon Porter Reel 1 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - b. Jeannie Robertson Copied by Jon Porter Reel 2 (Box 13)
  - a. Jeannie Robertson Copied by Jon Porter Reel 3 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - b. Jeannie Robertson Copied by Jon Porter Reel 4 (Box 13)
  - a. Jeannie Robertson Copied by Jon Porter Reel 5 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - b. Tribute to Jeannie (Box 13)
  - a. Tribute to Jeannie Robertson, Easter Sunday 1975 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - b. Several Scottish Singers (Box 13)
    Dodie Chalmers The Golden Vanity 286
    John Strachan Glenlogie 238
    Jimmy and Mrs. Miller Lord Randal
    John Strachan Clyde’s Water (The Mother malison) 216
    Willie Mathieson Bonnie Rantin’ Laddie 240
    Betsy Whyte Sweet William’s Ghost 77
    Ewen McColl Eppie Morie 223
    Jimmy McBeth The Broom of the Cowdenknowes 217
    Bella Stewart Higgins The Lowlands o’ Holland
    Bella Stewart Higgins The Douglas Tragedy
    Jeannie Robertson The Butcher Boy (The Miller’s Apprentice, SA, I, 407)
    Jeannie Robertson Peggy on the Banks o’ Spey (When I was new, But Sweet 16)
    John Strachan Three Jolly Butchers
    Bill Clark Ellon Feeing Market
    Ewing McColl Still Growin’ (College Boy)
  - a. Selection of 21 Gaelic songs. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - b. Gaelic Songs (Box 13)
  - a. Pat Boone (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Gloryland Way (Box 13)
  - Why Me (Box 13)
  - Campin’ in Canaan land (Box 13)
  - Where Will I Shelter My Sheep (Box 13)
  - Acres of Diamonds (Box 13)
  - I Feel Like Traveling On (Box 13)
  - Way Down Deep in My Soul (Box 13)
  - I’ll Meet You in Church Sunday Morning (Box 13)
  - Someone to Care (Box 13)
  - b. The Ballad, The Archetype, and Rock Music (Box 13)
  - Allman Brothers I (Box 13)
  - Allman Brothers II (Box 13)
  - a. Side 1 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Cornelius Watson (Box 13)
  - Ronie Watson (Box 13)
  - Side 2 (Box 13)
  - Ora Watson (Box 13)
  - Arlie Watson (Box 13)
  - Ora and Arlie Watson, and Gaither Carlton (Box 13)
  - b. Cindy Hunter, Interview regarding Jeannie Robertson, Edinburgh, June 29, 1979 (Box 13)
  - a. Andy Hunter’s Tape singing his own songs (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Banter between him, Jeannie, and others (Box 13)
  - Andy’s comments (Box 13)
  - b. Edinburgh Tape #1 (Box 13)
  - a. Jeannie Robertson excerpts from Peter Kennedy’s Cassette “What a Voice” (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - b. Side I (Box 13)
  - Readings by Joyce Collie and Alexander Fenton Side II (Box 13)
  - 6 Scottish and English Folksongs collected in Scotland (Box 13)
  - a. Interview with Jean Redpath (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - b. “The House Carpenter” (Box 13)
  - Joan Baez - “The Joan Baez Ballad Book” (Box 13)
  - Buffy Sainte Marie - “Little Wheel Spin and Spin” (Box 13)
  - Jean Ritchie - “British Traditional Ballads in the Southern Mountains” (Box 13)
  - Stefan Grossman - “Yazoo Basin Boogie” (Box 13)
  - a. Scottish and English Folk Songs collected in Scotland (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - b. Folktracks (cassette) (Box 13)
  - Not identified (Box 13)
  - Not identified (Box 13)